部
翻译校对       Mam
关
日  听      マキ
日听校对       Syura
翻译        银苹果
时间轴       鬼 忻奈
压制      娜夏
公
男
OP&ED       葉隠
Syura
校
诸神字幕组
高
男
樱
There might be a monster that comes out.
怪物が出て来るかもしれないな
So I have to try to find
Big Brother quickly.
だから早くお兄ちゃまを探さなきゃならないの
Big Brother is a handsome prince,
お兄ちゃまは素敵な王子様
so he'll be sure to defeat
the monster for me.
だから　きっと怪物を退治してくれるの
"Music Room #3"
- Welcome!
いらっしゃいませ
My, what an unusual guest
we have here, huh?
おや　これは珍しいお客様だなぁ
Welcome, my little lost kitty-cat.
ようこそ　迷子の子猫ちゃん
When I opened the door,
there were the police.
扉を開けると
そこは警察でした
"Big Brother is a Prince!"
Kitty-cat, where did you come from?
子猫ちゃん　どこから来たのかにゃ
Reverse harem!
逆ハーレム
This is a reverse harem!
逆ハーレムだ
This can't be right. Apparently,
there's still some water
こりゃいかん　プールで泳いだ時の水がまだ耳の中に残っているようだ
left in my ear from when
I was swimming at the pool.
総監殿　そうですよね
That must be it, Commissioner.
The reason why it sounded like
this little girl said "reverse harem"
こんなちっこい子が「逆ハーレム」なんて言ったような気がしたのは
must be because there's something
funny going on with our ears.
僕らの耳がおかしかったんですよねぇ
Debauchery.
酒池肉林
"Debauchery"
Yay! There's debauchery here!
わーい　ここ酒池肉林だぁ
"Glasses character"
眼鏡キャラ
"Boy Lolita"
ロリショタ
"Stoic type"
ストイック系
"Twincest"
近親相姦
"Bookworm"
ガリ勉
Big Brother...
お兄ちゃま…
You're blond, so you're Big Brother!
金髪だから　お兄ちゃま
We've never heard about this.
聞いてないよ
You have a younger sister?
妹なんていたの
いや　俺は確か一人っ子で
No, I am definitely an only child.
At least I think I'm an only child...
一人っ子だったと思うのだが…
Now that you mention it,
maybe you do kind of look alike.
言われてみれば　似てるかもしれないよね
二人とも金髪だし
You are both blond, and all.
For that matter, are "glasses character"
and "Big Brother" on the same level?
そもそも「眼鏡キャラ」と「お兄ちゃま」は同列の言葉なのか
It doesn't matter, does it?
She called me a "studyhound."
いいじゃないですか
自分なんてガリ勉ですよ
Um... Miss, what's your name?
えーと　お嬢ちゃん　お名前は？
Kirimi.
霧美（きりみ）
Kirimi?
切り身（きりみ）？
''kirimi: fillet"
Kirimi-chan, you've made
some kind of mistake, haven't you?
霧美ちゃん　何かの間違いじゃないかなぁ
I don't think that I have a younger sister.
多分俺に妹はいないはずなんだが
You're not my Big Brother,
even though you're blond?
金髪なのに　お兄ちゃまじゃないの
"Whimper"
M-me?
お…俺は…
"Whimper"
"Sensitive..."
All right. As of today, I will be
your Big Brother, your Big Brother!
分かった　今日から俺は君のお兄ちゃま　お兄ちゃまだよ
可愛い　可愛い
You're so cute, you're so cute...
No matter how easily carried away
by your feelings you may be,
いくら情に流されやすいからって
幼児にそんな無責任な発言していいと思ってんですか
do you really think you should make
such irresponsible declarations
to a child that young?
無責任じゃないもん
I'm not irresponsible!
I'll make sure I look after you!
ちゃんとお世話するもん
So come on home with me!
だからおうちにつれて帰るんだもん
What should we do, Kyoya- senpai?
どうしましょう　鏡夜先輩
ひょっとして高等部に実際に金髪のお兄さんがいるんじゃないか
It's just possible that
she actually does have
a blond older brother
in high school, isn't it?
Kirimi...
霧美　霧美
- Um, who are you?
あのう　どちらさま
外国の人だ
He's a foreigner!
っていうか　ドアの形変わってません？
And for that matter,
doesn't the door look different?
霧美
Kirimi...
Master...
お坊ちゃま
...you've forgotten your attire.
ご装束をお忘れです
"Black Magic Club President,
Nekozawa Umehito"
- Nekozawa- senpai?
猫澤先輩？！
"What was that!?"
Master Umehito is terribly
vulnerable to bright lights.
梅人坊ちゃまは明るい光が大の苦手
"Nekozawa family maid, Kuretake"
それゆえ　黒装束で身を包んでおられないと
As such, if he doesn't
shroud himself in black attire,
he cannot endure the brightness,
and will collapse.
明るさに耐え切れず倒れてしまわれるのでございます
ご本人の明るい髪の色さえ
He even has to cover the lightness of
the color of his hair with a dark wig!
暗い鬘で隠さないとダメなのです
"Nekozawa family secretary, Kadomatsu"
On the other hand, his sister,
Mistress Kirimi, hates dimly lit places.
逆に　妹君の霧美お嬢様は暗い所が大嫌いなのです
Then, she's Nekozawa- senpai's
younger sister?
この子は猫澤先輩の妹さんだったんですね
To tell the truth, that is correct.
何を隠そう　その通りでございます
"Nekozawa Kirimi"
き…き…霧美…
K-K-Kirimi...
ここに…　いたのか
...so this is where you are...
"Monster!"
ああ　お化け
Waah! A monster!
It's all right.
大丈夫　この呪い人形ベルゼネフはちっとも怖くないんだよ
The cursed puppet Belzenef here
is not the least bit scary.
猫澤家は代々猫を模ったものを崇拝してきたのだ
The Nekozawa family has worshipped
cat-shaped objects for generations.
No, it's not the puppet
that she's afraid of,
いえ　怖がってるのはその人形じゃなくて
猫澤先輩本人なのでは？
Nekozawa- senpai, it's you, yourself.
It's because of the way
you're dressed, isn't it?
そんな格好してるからじゃないの
"Trying to help"
Don't do that! It's so bright, I'll die!
やめてくれ　明るくて死ぬ
Well, we could just darken the room!
じゃ　部屋を暗くすればいいよ
暗いのいや
Waah! I hate the dark!
Oh, there, there.
So now, she can't take it.
今度はこっちがダメなのか
The tragedy that gave rise to
these two opposite personalities
この正反対の体質が生み出した悲劇性こそが
is the reason why these two are called
the Nekozawa Family's Romeo & Juliet.
まさにお二人が猫澤家のロミジュリと呼ばれる由縁なのでございます
ロミオとジュリエットって兄弟じゃないし
Romeo and Juliet weren't
brother and sister,
and the situation is greatly different.
状況が大分違うんですが…
I am aware of that.
存じております
It was just a snappy catch quote
that I came up with just now.
これは今私が思いついた素敵キャッチコピーにございます
I thought it would make it more dramatic.
よりドラマチックかと思いまして…
"The Nekozawa family's Romeo & Juliet"
Oh, I see.
ああ　そうですか
因みに我々は霧美さまのお迎え役でございます
Incidentally, we have been
sent to pick up Kirimi-sama.
猫澤家の人って
Is the whole Nekozawa family...
...as strange as all this?
みんなこんなに怪しいのかなぁ
何をおっしゃいますか
What are you talking about!?
The Nekozawas are a distinguished,
猫澤家はロシアのトカレフ王朝の系譜に属する
proper family, descended from
the Tokarev dynasty of Russia!
由緒正しき家系にございます
Tokarev?
トカレフ
"Tokarev"
ロマノフ王朝では？
D-don't you mean the Romanov dynasty?
But there's a legend that says that,
for whatever reason,
そして猫澤家には　何の因果か
"Ignored?"
何百年かに一度　梅人さまのように
once every few hundred years,
a person in the Nekozawa family is born,
who, like Umehito-sama, is fated
to be possessed by darkness...
闇に魅入られた運命の子が生まれるという言い伝えが…
...which may or may not be true.
あったりなかったりするんでございます
It may or may not be true?
あったりなかったりって…
So which is it?
どっちだよ
"Nekozawa Family Album"
The Master, as a result
of his condition, is unable
坊ちゃまはその体質ゆえ
黒装束なしで妹君に近づくことが叶わず
to go near his sister
without his black attire,
霧美お嬢様は肖像画でのみ知る
and Mistress Kirimi fell in love
with the fairy-tale prince
of an older brother that she
only knew from his portrait.
御伽話の王子様のような兄上に恋い焦がれ
After she learned that her older brother
was enrolled in high school,
高等部に兄上が在籍すると知ってからは
時折こうして梅人様のお姿を捜し求めるようになったのでございます
she's gotten so that she will come
looking for Umehito-sama like this.
Of course, we have repeatedly
tried to comfort the Mistress
もちろん　私どもも王子様ものの童話などで
with bedtime stories
of princely characters,
お嬢様をお慰めし続けてまいりましたが
and having run out of stories
to tell, we have lately added
さすがにネタが尽き
最近では王子キャラの出てくる少女漫画まで
shojo manga having prince characters
that appear in them to her repertoire,
レパートリーを広げて見ましたら
これがすっかり夢中になられて…
and she has gotten
utterly absorbed in them.
Shojo manga?
少女漫画？
Reverse harem!
逆ハーレムだ
Debauchery.
酒池肉林
Yay! There's debauchery here!
わーい　ここ酒池肉林だ
This maid was the source of that?
原因はこのメードか
Debauchery in shojo manga?
So then, Sashimi-chan doesn't...
少女漫画で酒池肉林…
って　それじゃ刺し身ちゃんは…
"Sashimi"
- That's kirimi.
- It's "Kirimi"!
切り身だろ
"kirimi (fillet)"
霧美っす
"Kirimi"
...Kirimi-chan doesn't know
that you're her older brother,
霧美ちゃんは猫澤先輩がお兄さんだと知らないんですか
Nekozawa- senpai?
はい　何度お話しても　信じては下さらず
Yes. We have told her many times,
but she just will not believe us.
Neko-chan must feel sad about that.
そんなの猫ちゃんが悲しいよ
Yes.
はい　ですから
Which is why...
こうやって霧美が暗闇を愛してくれるようにと
...I offer prayers like this, every night,
that Kirimi will come to love darkness.
毎晩お祈りを捧げております
No, you've got it backwards.
いや　逆だろう
You should get accustomed
to bright places.
あんたが明るいとこ平気になれよ
妹に何さす気だ
What are you trying
to do to your sister?
Come, Kirimi-sama.
さ　霧美さま
帰りましょう
Let's go home.
いや　お兄ちゃまと一緒するの
No!!
I'm staying with Big Brother!
I'd rather stay with Big Brother!
お兄ちゃまと一緒がいいんだもん
Nekozawa- senpai...
猫澤先輩…
That's okay, Suou- kun.
いいんです　須王君
It doesn't matter what happens to me.
私のことなどはどうでもいいんです
Please, please, give Kirimi
the love that she needs!
どうか…どうか霧美を可愛がってやってください
Nekozawa- senpai!
猫澤先輩
Siblings are such that they are
the source of problems, in any family.
兄弟というのはどこの家でも問題の種だなぁ
I'm jealous of them.
羨ましいですよ
I've been an only child my whole life.
自分はずっと一人っ子だったから
Yet, actually having a brother,
でも　せっかく兄弟がいるのに　仲良くできないなんて
but not getting along with him,
is kind of sad, huh?
なんか悲しいですよね
What's the matter, Big Brother?
どうしたの　お兄ちゃま
I'm sorry, Kirimi-chan.
I'm really not your big brother.
ごめんよ　霧美ちゃん
俺はやはり君のお兄ちゃまではないんだ
But don't you worry.
だけど　安心して
Kirimi-chan, you have a prince
that's even more handsome than me,
霧美ちゃんには　俺なんかよりもずっと素敵な王子様の
and he's your real Big Brother.
本物のお兄ちゃまがいるから
Senpai...
先輩…
Once she came here, Kirimi-chan
became a guest of the Host Club.
ここを訪れた以上
霧美ちゃんは我がホスト部のお客さまだ
Ouran Host Club exists in order
to bring happiness to girls.
我が桜蘭ホスト部は
女の子の幸せのために存在する
Having a brother and sister
that don't care for each other,
思いあう兄弟同士が一緒にいられないなど
and who can't be with each other,
is a serious problem that should not be!
あってはならぬ大問題
As of now, " Operation Reform
Nekozawa- senpai Into the Bright,
これより　猫澤先輩を霧美ちゃん好みの明るい王子様キャラに
Princely Character that
Kirimi-chan Prefers" is underway!
改革する大作戦を　開始する
"Or for short,"
"Operation Character Reformation"
- Again?
B-but...
し…しかし…
...reforming Umehito-sama's
dark-possessed character?
梅人さまの闇に魅入られたキャラを改革するなんて…
そんなことが可能だとでも？
Is that even possible?
だから　いくら情に流されやすいからって
Like I said, no matter how easily
carried away by feelings you may be,
these irresponsible declarations are...
そんな無責任な発言は…
Have you forgotten?
忘れたのか
We have someone on our side who
is more heartening than anyone else
我々にはキャラ設定の改革に関して
when it comes to altering
a person's character, do we not?
誰よりも心強い味方がついているではないか
By any chance...
それって？
...does he mean?
もしかして？
"Powerful motor"
Sure enough.
やっぱりねぇ
"Science Room #3"
"with darkroom capabilities"
Your golden hair, as it
flickers in the candlelight...
蝋燭に揺れる君の黄金の髪
Your shining, ivory skin...
輝く象牙の肌
Your smile, more mysterious than a flower,
illuminated by moonlight...
月光に照らされた一輪の花よりも神秘的なその微笑は
そう　まるで…
Yes, almost as if...
あたかも呪われし蝋人形のごとき禍々しさで
...as if you were a cursed wax statue,
with your malevolence-
Wrong!
ちがーう！
トンクラ　誰がそんなセリフを教えた
You numbskull!
Who told you to say that line!?
How many times do I have to tell you,
using occult terms is off-limits!?
オカルト用語は禁止と何度言えば分かるんじゃ
しかし　私の持つボキャブラリーはこういった類のものばかりで…
B-but, my vocabulary is limited
to these sorts of words.
Talking back to me is off-limits, too!
"Spartan education!"
口答えは禁止
王子様キャラたるもの　そう易々と女々しい言い訳はしない
A princely character doesn't come up
with such a sissy excuse so easily!
いい　影があるのはいいのよ 影があるのは
Remember, it's good to have a dark side.
"Hmph!" "Throb!"
"So you're all alone too?" "Throb!"
Solitary characters work
pretty well with young girls, too.
孤独なキャラは　幼い女の子にも結構効くのよ
だけど　今時オカルトやホラーなんてもってのほかですわ
"*cough cough*"
But these days, the occult, horror,
and the like are out of the question!
Mori- senpai, add another no-good word!
モリ先輩　NGワード 追加
Wax statue, right?
蝋人形…だな
Renge- kun is really ripping it up, huh?
蓮華君　飛ばしてるなあ
のりのりだよね
She's on a roll.
I'm not sure if those lines will
be practical for his sister, though.
妹相手に　あんなセリフが実用的かは知らないけど
Sir, are you just going to watch?
殿は見てるだけなの
Well, I don't want to end up cursed later.
だって　後で呪われたらイヤだもん
Okay, you seem to have learned most
of the character-altering lines.
さっ　キャラ設定変更のセリフも大分覚えたようですし
I think it's about time
we moved on to it.
今日もそろそろあれ　行ってみますわよ？
まっ　待ってくれ
Hold on! It's still far too
soon for me to attempt it!
あれはまだ私にはとても…
Evil beam!!
イビルビーム
Don't you let a mere
flashlight upset you!
"Ordinary flashlight"
懐中電灯ぐらいでうろたえない
Pluck up your nerve! It's not
a physical problem for you,
気合出して
体質的には問題ないんだから　要は根性の問題です
which means it's a problem of guts!
Edgar was able to deal with a cross
with his nerve and guts, right!?
エドガーだって　気合と根性で十字架あしらってたでしょう
オカルトを否定してたのでは…
I thought you rejected the occult.
フィクションはいいの
Fiction is all right. Fashion is not.
ファッションはダメ
Is that right?
そうなんだ
And you're the one...
自分はいつも
妙なコスプレしてるくせにねぇ
...who's always engaging
in weird cosplay.
You're not putting your whole heart
into saying these lines, either.
大体セリフに心がこもってませんわ
Think of your practice partner
as Kirimi-chan a bit more.
もっと練習相手を霧美ちゃんと思って
T-that's easy for you to say,
but Kirimi's face isn't as ashen as this.
そうは言いますが…
霧美はこんな土気色の顔では…
"It's actually more of a brown..."
T-that's easy for you to say,
but Kirimi's face isn't as ashen as this.
I don't want to hear it!
問答無用
Look with the eyes of your heart.
The eyes of your heart!
心の目で見るのです
心の目で
Yes! This is all for Kirimi-chan's sake!
そう　全ては霧美ちゃんのためだ
心の目を発動させれば
If you can put your mind's eye to work,
I'm sure that doll will look
like the actual Kirimi-chan!
きっとその人形が本物の霧美ちゃんに見えるはず
Here, sir!
はい　殿
We got this one ready, too.
こんなのも用意してみました
"Just a mannequin"
Go ahead and try speaking words
of love to this Haruhi doll, please.
それじゃこのハルヒ人形に愛を語ってみてください
"Expressionless"
T-this is Haruhi?
こ…これが…ハルヒ？
何事も先ず　お手本
You should always show by example first.
H-Haruhi... I...
ハ…ハルヒ　俺は…
"Mind's eye activating"
先輩…
Senpai...
Ahem...
あのう…
ああ　ハルヒ　ほん…本物？
H-Haruhi!? T-the real one?
W-when did you get here?
い…い…いつの間に…
Kirimi-chan came to
the club room again today.
今日も部室の方に霧美ちゃんが来てるんですけど…
If you've got time to goof around,
doing repulsive stuff like this,
気色悪いことして　遊ぶ暇があるなら
then could you please hang out
with Kirimi-chan for a little while?
霧美ちゃんの相手も少しはしてくれませんかねぇ
"Disgusting"
き…気色悪い!？
R-repulsive?
- Repulsive... repulsive... repulsive...
- What's wrong, Haruhi?
気色悪い
なんだ　ハルヒ　子供の相手は苦手か
- Repulsive... repulsive... repulsive...
- Aren't you any good with children?
- No, I don't dislike children or anything,
いえ　子供は嫌いじゃないんですけど…
but...
ガリ勉　もっと
Studyhound, more!
"Flashback"
"Throb! Throb! Throb!"
"They are all my love slaves now.
あいつらはもうみんな　私の恋の奴隷よ
"Throb! Throb! Throb!"
"Music Room #3"
Now, who shall I have
entertain me tonight?"
さ　今夜は誰に楽しませてもらおうかしら
She's had me read around 50 volumes
この三日間で　五十冊ほど少女漫画を朗読させられました
of shojo manga to her
these last three days.
And of all things, this stuff is really
full of reverse harems, and debauchery.
いやあ　ものによっては本当に逆ハーレムで　酒池肉林ですね
Big Brother?
お兄ちゃま？
このお部屋暗いよ
This room is too dark!
あっ　霧美ちゃん　部屋で待っててって言ったのに…
Ah, Kirimi- chan! I told you
to wait in the other room.
Oh, what's wrong, what's wrong?
うん　どうしたどうした
よ～ちよち　ほーら　もう怖くないよ
There, there, you see?
Nothing to be afraid of.
そ～れ
Senpai?
先輩？
I am a handsome, princely big brother...
私は素敵な王子様のお兄ちゃんだ
I'm not afraid of the light!
光なんか怖くない
Self evil beam!!
自分　イビルビーム
He did it!
やった
Nekozawa- senpai has finally become
able to shine a flashlight on himself!
猫澤先輩がついに自らを懐中電灯で照らせるように
ブラボー　ブラボー
Bravo, bravo.
Nekozawa- senpai...
猫澤先輩
You've done it! I'm sure that
Kirimi-chan will be thrilled, too!
やりましたね　霧美ちゃんもきっと喜びますよ
Look, Kirimi-chan.
This is your real Big Brother.
ほら　霧美ちゃん
これが本当のお兄ちゃまだよ
"This"
お兄ちゃま
Big Brother!
霧美
Kirimi!
Um, you're just complicating matters,
so could you stop that?
あのう　こういうのってややこしくなるんで　やめてもらえます
Huh? Did you say something?
え？　何か言ったか
It was nothing.
なんでもないです
Kirimi...
霧美
"Unspeakable terror"
Kirimi!
霧美
That evil beam just now...
今のイビルビームは
...must have been pretty scary, huh?
さすがに怖かったろうなぁ
Kirimi...
霧美…
Nekozawa- senpai...
猫澤先輩
Enough.
もういいんです
Even if I go through
any more special training,
これ以上特訓を受けたところで
there's no guarantee
that Kirimi will accept me...
霧美が私を受け入れてくれる保障もありませんし
Rather than Kirimi having me
for an older brother,
霧美も　こんな兄より
須王君がお兄さん代わりになってくれたほうが…
Suou- kun, you should be her
substitute older brother, instead.
You're the one that girl really
wants to see, aren't you?
あの子が本当に会いたいのはあんただろ
If you hold your sister dear,
then show more guts, even if it kills you!
妹が大事なら
もっと死ぬ気で根性見せろよ
Huh? Your sister is still
in the courtyard.
あれ　妹ちゃん　まだ中庭にいるよ
一緒に何かいるなぁ
There's something down
there with her...
Oh, it's a cat.
あっ　猫か
Your family sure does love cats.
さすが猫好き一家
You warm right up to even stray cats.
野良猫にもすぐ懐かれるんだ
違います
That's not true!
いくら猫澤家が猫を崇拝してても
Regardless of how the
Nekozawa family may revere cats,
there's no way that something as occult
だからって　野良猫と仲良くなれるなんて
as her being chummy with a
stray cat could happen, is there?
そんなオカルトなことがあるわけないじゃないですか
Kirimi is afraid of animals!
霧美は動物が苦手なんです
And live cats are what
she's most afraid of!
その中でも　生きた猫が一番怖いんです
霧美
Kirimi!!
Nekozawa- senpai!
猫澤先輩
Oh, no! He's not even
wearing his hood!
そんな　フードも被らずに…
Help!
助けて…
Kirimi!
霧美
Kirimi!!
お兄ちゃま
Big Brother!
He did it!
やったね
This is the result of my special training.
私の特訓の成果ですわ
You see, Kirimi? No need to be
afraid of that bad kitty anymore.
ほら　霧美　もう怖くないよ
あんな悪い猫は
With the power of this curse puppet,
Belzenef... I'll curse... curse...
この呪い人形ベルゼネフの力で…
呪って…呪っ…
"Music Room #3"
"Several days later"
Nekozawa- senpai...
猫澤先輩
あの時多分一生分ぐらいの日光を浴びたんだろうな
He probably took in a whole life's
worth of sunlight that day.
And he's reacted by reverting back
to his condition before the training.
その反動で　特訓前の状態に戻っちゃったんだね
Well, well,
やれやれ　結局またあの鬱陶しい黒装束を着てるわけね
that explains why he's wearing
those gloomy black clothes again.
But still...
だけど…
たとえ怪物が現れても　もう大丈夫
Now, even if monsters do appear,
I'll be all right.
After all, Kirimi has
a princely Big Brother now,
だって霧美には　自分が苦手なお日様の下に飛び出しても
who will fight to protect her,
even if it means dashing out under
the sun that he fears so much.
霧美を守って戦ってくれる王子様のお兄ちゃまがいるから
甘いもの大好き
I love sweets!
ってハニー先輩　虫歯になっても知りませんよ
Honey- senpai,
you're bound to get cavities.
Ow!
痛い
What did I just get done saying?
いってるそばから
俺の責任だ
I'm responsible.
Next time,
"Honey- senpai's Three Bitter Days"
桜蘭高校ホストクラブ　来週も
Ouran High School Host Club will
be waiting for you, next week!
お待ちしております